Hagoromo-kun! Why are you just standing around?
¡Hagoromo! ¿Por qué estás ahí parado?
Assistant Manager Hagoromo!
¡Asistente de gerente Hagoromo!
Oh, Mr. Branch Manager.
Oh, el gerente de la sucursal.
Don't give me that! Did you send Inokuma Yawara home?
¡No me contestes así! ¿Mandaste a Yawara Inokuma a su casa?
Yes, sir, right on schedule.
Sí, señor, a horario.
Right on schedule? You're supposed to send her home earlier!
¿A horario? ¡Tenías que desligarla antes!
Listen, you don't have to give her any work!
Escucha, no debes darle ningún trabajo.
The higher-ups said to let her concentrate on judo!
Los ejecutivos dijeron que se debe concentrar en el judo.
U-Understood.
Entendido.
Geez! It's not like you do any work around here yourself!
Diablos, no es como si tú trabajaras siquiera.
Mr. Hagoromo, I've made the reservations!
Ya hice las reservaciones, señor Hagoromo.
I've made the reservations.
Ya hice las reservaciones.
I-I see. So you've made the reservations.
Ya veo. Así que hiciste las reservaciones.
Now here's something you don't see every day.
Eso es algo que no se ve todos los días.
So Hagoromo-kun got himself a reservation? Probably nothing worth mentioning.
¿Así que Hagoromo consiguió unas reservaciones? Aunque probablemente no sea importante.
Kato Chu, huh?
¿Kato Chu?
K-Kato Chu Company?!
¡¿Kato Chu?!
Hokkaido and the Martial Arts Hall
"Hokkaido y el Auditorio Nacional"
Let's give a hand to Assistant Manager Hagoromo!
¡Un aplauso para el asistente de gerente Hagoromo!
Look, now wait.
No, esperen.
I thought you just sat around and read the sports papers.
Pensaba que te pasabas el día leyendo el periódico.
I can't believe you landed a deal with Kato Chu Company.
No puedo creer que hayas conseguido un trato con Kato Chu.
Like they say, a good hawk hides its claws.
Como dice el refrán: "el halcón inteligente esconde sus garras".
R-Right.
Sí.
So it's scheduled from April 21st to the 23rd, eh?
¿Así que está programado del 21 al 23 de abril?
If we make that three-day outing a success, Kato Chu will become our loyal customer.
Si logramos que sea un éxito, Kato Chu se convertirá en un cliente leal.
Y-Yeah.
Sí.
A major corporation like Kato Chu will be a huge boost for our firm!
Una gran empresa como Kato Chu dará un gran impulso a nuestra compañía.
It will also be a major blow to their former exclusive travel firm, Honami Travel.
Y además será un golpe mayúsculo a su anterior agencia de viajes, Viajes Honami.
Inokuma-san needs to be there with us!
Inokuma debe ir con nosotros.
U-Uh, excuse me...
Disculpe...
Sign: Tsurukame Travel# All right, we're calling the home office!
#Viajes Tsurukame ¡Muy bien, llamaremos a la oficina central!
H-Hey, now wait! Sign: Tsurukame Travel#
¡Esperen! #Viajes Tsurukame
Inokuma-san, you look tired.
Pareces cansada, Inokuma.
Work's been very hard.
El trabajo es muy duro.
I attract a lot of attention because I'm just starting out.
@Todos están pendientes de mí porque recién comienzo.
Huh?
¿Eh?
"Work's been very hard"!
¿"El trabajo es muy duro"?
If Beanpole can't set her straight, then I'm taking matters into my own hands!
Si la larguirucha no puede enderezarla, me encargaré yo mismo.
That idiot office girl!
¡Esa tonta oficinista!
You're too loud!
¡Haces mucho ruido!
Pipe down and eat your fruit parfait!
Guarda silencio y come tu helado.
But one thing at work did go well!
Pero algo en el trabajo salió fenomenal.
It was so exhilarating!
¡Fue muy estimulante!
So is it...
¿Dirías que sentiste lo mismo que cuando logras un ippon seoi?
That's slick, Beanpole.
Eres hábil, larguirucha.
That's my fruit parfait!
¡Ese es mi helado!
Cut it out, Fujiko-san! Work is nothing like judo.
Claro que no, Fujiko. El trabajo no es para nada como el judo.
Y-You're right.
Tienes razón.
You have no delicacy!
¡Te falta delicadeza!
Don't interfere!
¡No te metas!
Uh, um...
Escucha...
Actually, Inokuma-san...
En realidad, Inokuma...
You must also be working hard at Saikai University every day.
Tú también estás trabajando duro en la Universidad Saikai.
Let's both go all out at the All-Japan Championships.
Las dos debemos dar nuestro mejor esfuerzo en el Abierto Nacional.
Bo...
Las dos...
"Both"? Inokuma-san, are you going to enter?
¿"Las dos"? ¿Tú vas a participar, Inokuma?
I have to! You're entering too!
Tengo que hacerlo, ya que tú también participarás.
Thank you, Inokuma-san!
¡Gracias, Inokuma!
I felt so helpless and alone!
¡Me sentía sola y desamparada!
Fujiko-san!
¡Fujiko!
I didn't know what I'd do if you didn't enter!
¡No sabía qué haría si no participabas!
Fujiko-san...
Fujiko...
Looky there! It all went according to my original plans!
Vaya, todo fue de acuerdo a mi plan original.
Good, now I have my front page spread!
Muy bien, ya tengo mi primera plana.
"Inokuma Yawara's Friendship Burns Bright!
"La amistad de Yawara Inokuma arde intensamente".
She's Entering the All-Japan Championships!"
"Participará en el Abierto Nacional".
Inokuma-san, let's do our best at the April 22nd All-Japan Championships!
Inokuma, demos nuestro mejor esfuerzo el 22 de abril en el Abierto Nacional.
Okay!
Sí.
April... 22nd?
¿El 22 de abril?
What's wrong?
¿Qué sucede?
N-Nothing's wrong!
No, nada.
Excuse me! Two more fruit parfaits, please!
Disculpe, dos copas más, por favor.
Make 'em extra large!
Que sean extra grandes.
Let's go for it!
@¡A ganar!
What will I do? I completely forgot!
¿Qué hago? ¡Lo olvidé por completo!
On April 22nd, I'll...
El 22 de abril yo...
Sign: Hagoromo#
#Hagoromo
I'm home.
Ya llegué.
There's no dinner left, dear.
No sobró nada de la cena, cariño.
Huh? Okay.
¿Qué? No hay problema.
Honey, I'm going to be leaving on the 21st.
Querida, tengo que viajar el 21.
Are you "blowing off some steam" again?
¿Otra vez tienes que liberar estrés?
No, it's for work.
No, es por el trabajo.
We managed to land a big company today.
Logramos un trato con una gran empresa.
Who did?
¿Quién lo hizo?
Me.
Yo.
Really, you never get any big assignments.
Cielos, nunca consigues nada importante.
Yeah, you're right.
Sí, tienes razón.
Katsuo, do you play judo?
Katsuo, tú haces judo, ¿no es así?
Do you?
¿No es así?
I just got back from cram school!
Acabo de volver del @curso de admisión.
So you say.
Ya veo.
Hey, food...
Oye, la comida...
There's no food.
No hay nada.
So you say.
Ya veo.
Sign: Tsurukame Travel Shinbocho Branch Office#
#Viajes Tsurukame - Sucursal Shinbocho
Headline: A Three-Way Matchup!!#
#@¡Enfrentamiento triple!
Sidebar: Inokuma Yawara's Friendship Burns Bright! She's Entering the All-Japan Championships!# Headline: A Three-Way Matchup!!#
#La amistad de Yawara Inokuma arde intensamente #Participará en el Abierto Nacional
Inokuma Yawara is really something! Sidebar: Inokuma Yawara's Friendship Burns Bright! She's Entering the All-Japan Championships!# Headline: A Three-Way Matchup!!#
¡Yawara Inokuma es impresionante!
I'm starting to get excited!
¡Ya me estoy emocionando!
And this Matsuda reporter writes his stories with such passion!
Y este reportero Matsuda escribe con mucha pasión.
Headline: All-Japan Women's Championship All Sports Daily#
#Abierto Nacional de Judo Femenino #Todos los Deportes
It's why I can't drop All Sports. Headline: All-Japan Women's Championship All Sports Daily#
Por eso no puedo dejar el Todos los Deportes.
Mr. President, you didn't have to come all the way here!
No hacía falta que venga personalmente, señor presidente.
Sign: Branch Manager's Office# We could have come to you!
#Oficina del gerente de sucursal Podríamos haber ido nosotros.
No, I really need to meet the guy who snatched Kato Chu from Honami Travel.
No, debía conocer al hombre que arrebató a Kato Chu de las garras de Viajes Honami.
What will I do?
¿Qué haré?
On April 22nd...
El 22 de abril...
Screen: Input Error, repeated#
#Error de entrada
How should I proceed?
¿Qué debo hacer?
I see, the All-Japan Championships, huh? Guess I'll go cheer her on.
Ya veo, el abierto nacional. Supongo que debería ir a alentarla.
So when is it?
¿Cuándo es?
Here he is, sir, Assistant Manager Hagoromo.
Aquí está, señor. El asistente de gerente Hagoromo.
Oh, so it's you?!
¿Así que es usted?
You've done well. You've done very well!
Has hecho un gran trabajo. En verdad, felicitaciones.
Hagoromo-kun?
¿Hagoromo?
Assistant Manager Hagoromo!
¡Asistente de gerente Hagoromo!
You did great! That's one hell of an acquisition!
¡Gran trabajo! Fue una adquisición impresionante.
Mr. President!
¡Señor presidente!
Come on, pull yourself together!
¡Vamos, reacciona!
What'll I do?
¿Qué hago?
Headline: April 22nd A Historic Matchup!!#
#22 de abril #¡Un enfrentamiento histórico!
Sign: Kato Chu Company#
#Kato Chu
What now? Inokuma-kun must've forgotten about the date of the All-Japan!
¿Qué hago? Inokuma debe haberse olvidado de la fecha del abierto.
There's no other way. I have to change the schedule.
No hay otra manera. Debo cambiar las fechas.
Yes, that's what I'll do.
Sí, eso haré.
I-If I let this assignment get away from me, I'll... My life...
No puedo dejar que esto se me escape. Yo... con mi vida...
G-Good morning to you!
¡Buenos días!
What's the meaning of this?!
¡¿Qué significa esto?!
Right.
Verá.
The date of the tournament clashes with our trip!
¡La fecha del torneo coincide con nuestro viaje!
Inokuma Yawara can't possibly come!
Es imposible que Yawara Inokuma venga con nosotros.
Yes, that's why I'm here. Now, about the dates...
Por eso es que estoy aquí. Acerca de las fechas...
That malarkey you fed us has put us in a tight spot!
Esas tonterías que nos dijo nos ha metido en un aprieto.
Our potential partners have their own constraints.
Nuestro socios tienen sus compromisos.
We need to land the deal before Golden Week.
Debemos conseguir el trato antes de la semana puente.
We can't change days.
No podemos cambiar la fecha.
Y-You can't?
¿No pueden?
If Inokuma Yawara isn't coming, then forget we ever talked!
Si Yawara Inokuma no viene, entonces olvida nuestro trato.
Y-You can't!
¡Eso no!
You can also kiss our plan to switch over from Honami Travel goodbye!
También puedes despedirte de la idea de renunciar a Viajes Honami.
D-Don't worry!
No se preocupe.
Don't worry about what?
¿Que no me preocupe?
Uh, well... the thing is, Inokuma...
Verá... La cosa es que Inokuma...
She won't be in the tournament!
No participará en el torneo.
She won't?
¿Que no participará?
Are you crazy? It's the All-Japan. Of course she'll be in it!
¿Estás loco? Es el abierto nacional. Por supuesto que participará.
Uh, the truth is... Inokuma is injured.
La verdad es que Inokuma está lesionada.
Y-Yes! She's not entering the tournament because of a hip injury!
Así es. No participará en el torneo debido a una lesión en la cadera.
Is that true? So she'll be able to take this job?
¿Es eso cierto? ¿Entonces podrá viajar con nosotros?
Yes! There's no need to worry!
Sí, no hay razón para preocuparse.
Oh, so that's why you came here? Now I can relax.
Así que por eso viniste. Ahora puedo relajarme.
Inokuma Yawara will be coming with us on April 21st?
Yawara Inokuma viajará con nosotros el 21 de abril.
Yes!
Así es.
What now?
¿Qué hago?
I've really told a whopper.
Fue una mentira enorme.
If this assignment goes well, I'll finally turn my failed life around.
Si este negocio va bien, finalmente podré enderezar mi vida de fracasos.
But I'm sure she's going to enter the All-Japan.
Pero estoy seguro de que ella participará en el abierto nacional.
She's going to win it all with her Ippon Zeoi,
Ella vencerá a todas con su ippon seoi,
while I'll lose by a different sort of Ippon and become a laughingstock.
mientras que yo sufriré otra clase de golpe y me convertiré en un hazmerreír.
Y-You have an assignment...
¿Tienes un trabajo...?
w-with Kato Chu Company?
¿... con Kato Chu?
Yes.
Sí.
I-I see.
Ya veo.
The executive that Kato Chu is dealing with is a huge fan of Yawara-san.
El ejecutivo que está negociando con Kato Chu es un gran admirador de Yawara.
There's no better way to schmooze him than by using her.
No hay mejor forma de ablandarlo que usándola.
What should I do?
¿Qué debería hacer?
They just made me president of Honami Travel, and now this happens?
¿Acaban de hacerme presidente de Viajes Honami y pasa esto?
Kato Chu is Honami Travel's biggest account!
Kato Chu es el cliente más importante de Viajes Honami.
Um...
@Kazamatsuri...
That's a very complicated problem!
Es un problema muy complicado.
Let me think it over very carefully!
Debo pensarlo cuidadosamente.
Okay.
Sí.
Kazamatsuri-san is really thinking about me seriously.
Kazamatsuri piensa en mí con seriedad.
Compose yourself. Think about this logically.
Debo recuperarme. Pensar con lógica.
If Yawara-san enters the tournament...
Si Yawara participa en el torneo...
Sign: President's Office#
#Oficina del presidente
Honami Travel won't lose a big account, and I, the president...
Viajes Honami no perderá a un cliente importante, y yo, como presidente...
Hell, yeah!
¡Viva!
But if Yawara-san faces the new superpowered Sayaka-san...
Pero si Yawara se enfrenta a la nueva y superpoderosa Sayaka...
and she loses...
... y llegara a perder...
my company will be safe, but at the cost of my bachelorhood.
Mi compañía estará a salvo, pero al costo de mi soltería.
But if Yawara-san spurns the match and succeeds on her company outing,
Pero si Yawara renuncia al torneo y tiene éxito con su compañía,
Honami Travel will suffer a huge blow,
Viajes Honami sufrirá un duro golpe,
and I, the company president, will be in big trouble.
y yo, como presidente de la compañía, estaré en grandes problemas.
But if she doesn't enter the tournament,
Pero si no participa en el torneo,
Sayaka-san won't get her match with Yawara-san.
Sayaka no tendrá su enfrentamiento con Yawara.
Sign: So you ran away, Inokuma Yawara!#
#¡Así que escapaste, Yawara Inokuma!
Which means...
Lo que significa que...
my marriage with Sayaka-san will be put on indefinite hold,
mi casamiento con Sayaka estará suspendido indefinidamente,
and I'll be free as a bird!
y seré libre como un pájaro.
But...
Pero...
Um, I'm really sorry...
Lo siento.
for coming to you with this problem.
No debí traerte mis problemas.
Don't be!
No te preocupes.
L-Let me make a call.
Déjame hacer una llamada.
That's right, Kato Chu Company.
Así es, Kato Chu.
I want to know how much business we get from them per year.
Quiero saber cuantos ingresos conseguimos de ellos al año.
Yes, just give me a rough estimate.
Sí, una estimación estará bien.
Are you okay, Kazamatsuri-san?
¿Estás bien, Kazamatsuri?
You look pale.
Te ves muy pálido.
Twenty... Twenty billion...
Veinte... veinte mil millones...
Huh?
¿Qué?
Twenty billion yen.
Veinte mil millones de yenes.
I'm sorry for causing you so much trouble.
Perdón por causarte problemas.
I guess I need to make the decision myself.
Supongo que debo tomar esta decisión yo misma.
Th-That's...
Eso...
Who cares about twenty billion yen or Honami Travel?
¿A quién le importan veinte mil millones de yenes o Viajes Honami?
My... My happiness, my freedom...
Mi felicidad, mi libertad...
Y-Yawara-san!
¡Yawara!
You have to remember that your job comes first!
Tienes que recordar que tu trabajo es lo primero.
A life with just judo is not a life worth living!
Una vida sólo con el judo no vale la pena.
A woman's path in the world starts in the workplace!
El camino de una mujer en el mundo comienza en el trabajo.
Who cares about the All-Japan Championships?!
¿A quién le importa el Abierto Nacional?
Take that trip to Hokkaido!
¡Debes ir a ese viaje a Hokkaido!
And make sure you show them a good time!
Y debes asegurarte de que la pasen fenomenal.
Okay!
Sí.
Still, marrying Sayaka-san would guarantee me a good life.
Aún así, casarme con Sayaka me aseguraría una buena vida.
Are you willing to throw all of that away, Shinnosuke?
¿Estoy dispuesto a arrojar por la borda todo eso?
But I still have Fujiko-san.
Pero también está Fujiko.
Next!
¡Siguiente!
The more I observe, the more fearsome she looks.
Mientras más la veo, más temible se vuelve.
Yawara-san, your father made her into a true rival!
Yawara, tu padre la convirtió en una verdadera rival.
Next!
¡Siguiente!
I made the right decision.
Tomé la decisión correcta.
If I married Sayaka-san as soon as she defeated Yawara-san...
Si me casara con Sayaka ni bien ella derrote a Yawara...
You gotta be kidding!
¡No es broma!
I-I'm really glad she's going on that corporate trip.
En verdad es un alivio que vaya a ese viaje de la empresa.
I-Is that really Honami Sayaka?!
¿En verdad es Sayaka Honami?
Sh-She's like a whole 'nother person!
¡Es como si fuera otra persona!
I can't believe she's become that good!
¡No puedo creer que haya mejorado tanto!
You won't come out of this one unscathed, Yawara-san!
¡No podrás salir ilesa de esta, Yawara!
In just a little while...
Dentro de poco...
In just a little while, I will end our feud.
Dentro de poco pondré fin a nuestra disputa.
Wash your neck and prepare for your hanging, Inokuma Yawara!
Prepárate a morir, Yawara Inokuma.
What will I do? There's only one week left.
¿Qué hago? Sólo falta una semana.
What should I say?
¿Qué le digo?
If I tell Fujiko-san now that I can't enter the tournament...
Si le digo a Fujiko que no puedo participar en el torneo...
But I promised her we'd enter together.
&Pero le prometí que participaríamos las dos.
Inokuma-kun!
&¡Inokuma!
Inokuma-kun?
¿Inokuma?
Yes?
¿Sí?
Just so you know, we'll be having dinner on the 21st when we arrive.
Te informo que el 21 al llegar tendremos la cena.
Of course!
Sí, entendido.
So... we'll be reserving a table at the Restaurant Nociété Ailes?
Veamos... reservaremos una mesa en el restaurante Nociété Ailes.
I'll call them right away!
Les llamaré ahora mismo.
See? We may be discussing her assignment,
Ya veo. Puede que estemos discutiendo este trabajo,
but her heart's at the All Japan Championships.
pero su corazón está en el Abierto Nacional.
Even today's All Sports News is buzzing with reports that her rival, Honami Sayaka,
Hoy mismo, el Todos los Deportes tiene informes de que su rival, Sayaka Honami,
Headline: Honami Sayaka's Transformation#
se ha convertido en otra persona para poder derrotar a Inokuma.
has completely remade herself in order to beat Inokuma.
#La transformación de Sayaka Honami
It's over.
Todo se acabó.
There's no point in discussing this assignment.
No tiene sentido hablar de este trabajo.
Still, couldn't she say she can't go on this trip because of the tournament?
Sin embargo, ¿no podría decirme que no puede ir al viaje debido al torneo?
That way I can give up and move on.
De esa forma podría rendirme y seguir con otra cosa.
And there's also the dinner the next night on the 22nd.
También está la cena del 22.
L-Look, Inokuma-kun.
Escucha, Inokuma.
Yes, sir?
¿Dígame?
Uh, well...
Verás...
H-How are you feeling?
¿Cómo te sientes?
Oh, very well!
Muy bien.
I'll do my best next weekend.
Daré mi mejor esfuerzo el próximo fin de semana.
Uh, yeah. I know you will.
Sí, sé que lo harás.
So she is entering the tournament.
Entonces participará en el torneo.
Does she have any idea how big this assignment is?
¿Tiene idea de lo importante que es este negocio?
O-Or how it could change my life?
¿O cómo puede cambiarme la vida?
I'm exhausted.
Estoy exhausta.
But the tournament is just around the corner. I have to work hard!
Pero el torneo se aproxima. Debo esforzarme.
The All Japan Championships are just two days away!
¡Sólo faltan dos días para el Abierto Nacional!
Mm-hmm.
Sí.
I was nervous at the beginning, but now I'm brimming with courage!
Al inicio estaba muy nerviosa, pero ahora reboso de coraje.
R-Right.
Sí.
I'm sure it's because we'll be together!
Es gracias a que lo haremos juntas.
What's wrong, Inokuma-san?
¿Qué sucede, Inokuma?
Fujiko-san, the truth is I...
Fujiko, la verdad es que yo...
Honey, what would you say if, for example...
Cariño, que dirías si, por ejemplo...
If I got fired, what would you do?
Si me despidieran, ¿qué harías?
What?
Dime.
So you did mess up in some way!
Sabía que lo arruinarías.
I thought it was strange that you finally got a big assignment!
Ya me parecía raro que consiguieras un trajo importante.
N-No, I didn't.
No, claro que no.
If you're starting to get any big ideas, then you'd better just sit tight and do nothing!
Si se te empiezan a ocurrir grandes ideas, mejor siéntate y no hagas nada.
We need money for a down payment on a house!
Necesitamos el dinero para la hipoteca.
Katsuo needs to go to a private middle school in order to get into a good university!
Katsuo necesita ir a una secundaria privada para entrar a una buena universidad.
D-Don't worry! I was just asking "what if."
No te preocupes. Era sólo una suposición.
Don't joke around! Honestly!
¡No hagas esas bromas! ¡Cielo santo!
A good university, huh?
Una buena universidad...
Hey, food.
Oye, la comida...
There is no food.
No hay nada.
So you say.
Ya veo.
Sign: Tokyo International Airport#
#Aeropuerto Internacional de Tokio
Why am I waiting?
¿A quién espero?
She's going to the All Japan Championships tomorrow.
Ella irá al Abierto Nacional mañana.
Kato Chu Company and their guests are coming soon, expecting to see Inokuma Yawara.
Kato Chu y sus invitados vendrán pronto, esperando ver a Yawara Inokuma.
Then my lie will be exposed.
Entonces se expondrá mi mentira.
It will all be over.
Todo se terminó.
Will they fire me?
¿Me despedirán?
I'm sorry for being late!
¡Perdón por la demora!
They'll definitely fire me.
Seguramente me despedirán.
My life will continue to be one long losing streak.
Mi vida es un continuo fracaso.
Assistant Manager Hagoromo!
¡Asistente de gerente Hagoromo!
I'm sorry for being late, Assistant Manager Hagoromo!
¡Perdón por la demora, asistente de gerente Hagoromo!
Sign: The Barcelona Olympics in 145 Days
#Faltan 145 días para #los Juegos Olímpicos de Barcelona.
Yawara!
¡Yawara!
Where'd that screwy little bubblehead go?!
¡¿Adónde fue esa cabeza llena de aire?!
I'm sorry, Fujiko-san, I have to...
Lo siento, Fujiko, yo debo...
H-Hokkaido?!
¡¿Hokkaido?!
I'm taking you back! Right now, on the double!
¡Te traeré de vuelta! ¡Ya mismo, en este instante!
I'm grabbing you by the scruff of your neck and taking you back!
¡Te traeré de vuelta agarrándote de la nuca!
A-Assistant Manager Hagoromo, what did you just say?
¿Qué dijo, asistente de gerente Hagoromo?
Yawara!
¡Yawara!
You're Not Losing by Default!
¡No perderás por abandono!
You'll be getting my Osoto Gari if you don't watch!
Sufrirás mi osoto gari si no lo miras. $Osoto-gari: barrida exterior.